<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-11T15:40:06+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Abdul-Lateef Haji-Ali</title><subtitle>A personal website.</subtitle><author><name>Abdul-Lateef Haji-Ali</name><email>a.hajiali@hw.ac.uk</email></author><entry><title type="html">Fully-funded PhD Position: _Statistical Control of the Ecological Risks of Fisheries_</title><link href="/posts/phd-bas-advert" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fully-funded PhD Position: _Statistical Control of the Ecological Risks of Fisheries_" /><published>2020-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/phd-bas</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/phd-bas-advert">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hw.ac.uk/uk/schools/mathematical-computer-sciences/departments/actuarial-maths-statistics.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Department of Statistics and Actuarial
Mathematics&lt;/a&gt;
at &lt;a href=&quot;http://hw.ac.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Heriot-Watt University&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bas.ac.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;British Antarctic
Survey&lt;/a&gt; invites applications for a PhD position for the project
“&lt;em&gt;Statistical Control of the Ecological Risks of Fisheries&lt;/em&gt;” under the primary supervision of
Abdul-Lateef Haji-Ali from HWU and Co-Supervision of Simeon Hill and Norman Ratcliffe from BAS.
Successful applicants will be considered for funding for up to 3.5 years on EPSRC stipend level
in addition to tuition fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This PhD project will use state-of-the-art statistical methods to analyse the dynamics involved
in fisheries and develop new tools for managing the ecological and financial impacts of
fishing. Fishing competes with predators, such as birds and seals, for resources and might
impact their populations. The analysis of ecosystem dynamics will make use of extensive data
including remote sensed environmental variables and time series of bird, mammal and fish
population and performance estimates. The results of this analysis will then be used in a
simulation framework to develop and test feedback methods for managing the fisheries to control
the risks to marine ecosystems while maintaining economic benefits of fishing. In addition to
working on this project, the PhD candidate will be expected to enrol in several PhD level
courses in the &lt;a href=&quot;www.maxwell.ac.uk&quot;&gt;Maxwell Institute&lt;/a&gt; during the first year of the PhD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For full consideration, please apply by &lt;strong&gt;December 1st 2020&lt;/strong&gt;. The starting date is in
September 2021 or sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hwacuk.elluciancrmrecruit.com/Admissions/Pages/Login.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Apply Now&lt;/a&gt; (You will need
to create an account to start the application process. For the research statement simply state
the title of the project: “&lt;em&gt;Statistical Control of the Ecological Risks of Fisheries&lt;/em&gt;”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any further enquiries about the position, please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:a.hajiali@hw.ac.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Abdul-Lateef Haji-Ali&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Abdul-Lateef Haji-Ali</name><email>a.hajiali@hw.ac.uk</email></author><summary type="html">The Department of Statistics and Actuarial Mathematics at Heriot-Watt University and the British Antarctic Survey invites applications for a PhD position for the project “Statistical Control of the Ecological Risks of Fisheries” under the primary supervision of Abdul-Lateef Haji-Ali from HWU and Co-Supervision of Simeon Hill and Norman Ratcliffe from BAS. Successful applicants will be considered for funding for up to 3.5 years on EPSRC stipend level in addition to tuition fees.</summary></entry></feed>